aboutmyplace.co.uk 2016-11-26

# Terms of use and privacy policy

### Who we are

We are Rightmove Group Limited (company number 03997679) and our address is Turnberry House, 30 Caldecotte Lake Drive, Caldecotte, Milton Keynes, MK7 8LE (referred to as "we" or "us" or "our"). We are the providers of the website [www.rightmove.co.uk](http://www.rightmove.co.uk/) (referred to as the "Site"). Our VAT number is 918501823. We are registered as a Data Controller with the Information Commissioner's Office with registration number Z4726900.

We provide this Site to our members so that they can advertise their properties online. Our members include estate agents, commercial agents, letting agents, landlords, new homes developers and overseas property owners to display properties they are marketing. We are not an estate agency.

A reference to "you" or "your" is a reference to a user of the Site or any of our services.

### INTRODUCTION

We are committed to protecting your privacy. This privacy policy (referred to as the "Policy") explains how and for what purposes we use the information collected about you. Please read this Policy carefully. By using this Site and any services we offer via this Site, you are agreeing and consenting to the processing of your data as set out below. We sometimes use your data to provide additional marketing or communication services but you can always opt out of this. For more information, see the Marketing and Communication section of this Policy.

This Policy only relates to the personal information that we collect about you from the Site or from third parties such as social media companies. It does not relate to property information provided to us by our members. If you have a query about information relating to your property on the Site, please contact your estate agent or lettings agent directly or alternatively contact us at the details shown here.

### CONTACTING US

If you would like to opt out of marketing and communications from us and our nominated third parties, please contact us via email at [rightmover@rightmove.co.uk](mailto:rightmover@rightmove.co.uk) or please write to the Customer Services Team, Turnberry House, 30 Caldecotte Lake Drive, Caldecotte, Milton Keynes, MK7 8LE.

If you have any questions about this Policy or our use of your personal information, or if you wish to unsubscribe from marketing and communication messages from us or would like to submit a subject access request, please contact us via email at [CompanySecretary@rightmove.co.uk](mailto:CompanySecretary@rightmove.co.uk) or please write to The Company Secretary, Turnberry House, 30 Caldecotte Lake Drive, Caldecotte, Milton Keynes, MK7 8LE.

### WHAT PERSONAL DATA DO WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU?

**Information you give us:** We will collect the information that you give to us when using our Site. If you choose to access a particular search feature or to fill in a form on the Site, you may be asked to provide information about yourself, such as your name and contact details. We may also collect other information about you at the same time, such as details of the sort of property you are interested in, the cost and location of the property etc. We will also collect information that you provide to us when you register as a Rightmove user, request property email updates, participate in discussion boards or other social media functions on our Site or websites operated by associated third parties and enter into competitions, promotions or surveys. We will also collect information that you provide to us by corresponding with us by phone, e-mail or otherwise.

**Information we collect about you:** This is different to "information you give us" because it relates to technical data that we collect. So for example, we may collect technical information that has the potential to identify you, such as the internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the internet, your login information, browser type and version, time zone setting, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform. We may also collect information about your visit, including the full uniform resource locators (URL) clickstream to, through and from our Site (including date and time), products you viewed or searched for, page response times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks and mouse-overs), methods used to browse away from the page and any phone number used to call our customer service number. We may also keep a record of the advertisers or partners you contact and the contents of the emails you send to them.

**Information we receive about you from third parties:** We may receive information about you if you use any of the other websites we operate or the other services we provide. In this case we will have informed you, when we collected that data, that it may be shared internally and combined with data collected on this Site. We are also working closely with third parties (including, for example, social media platforms, business partners, sub-contractors in technical, payment and delivery services, advertising networks, analytics providers, search information providers and credit reference agencies) and may receive information about you from them.

### WHAT DO WE DO WITH YOUR PERSONAL DATA?

#### Main Uses of Your Data

This section of the Policy describes the things that we do with your data which relate directly to your use of the Site and our services. They are the things that we hope you would expect us to do with your information. We will use your information:

  * to provide the services available on our Site to you;
  * when you consent to us doing so, to pass your searches and messages on to our members, which include estate agents, commercial agents, lettings agents, developers, landlords or overseas private vendors to help them communicate with you directly and to provide a more personalised service to you. This may include contacting you about other relevant properties, adding you to their enquiry database for future contact and offering you their additional services;
  * to provide services and information to third parties and our members, which they can use to benchmark their performance;
  * customise and enrich your experience on our Site;
  * to allow you to participate in the interactive services available on our Site or to participate in competitions or promotions via our Site;
  * to enforce our [Terms of Use located here](http://www.rightmove.co.uk/this-site/terms-of-use-and-privacy-policy.html);
  * to contact you for your views on our services and to notify you occasionally about important changes to our Terms of Use or this Policy or developments to this Site or our services; and
  * to deliver relevant advertising to you whilst you are on the Site.

#### Technical Uses

This section of the Policy describes the things that we do with your data that arise from our monitoring of the Site and the collection of your information whilst using the Site. We may use this information:

  * to identify patterns that we can use in our marketing strategy and to help us develop, administer, support and improve our services and features and adverts;
  * to conduct reviews that assist us in the improvement and optimisation of our Site;
  * to ensure that content from our Site is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer;
  * to administer our Site and for internal operations, including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, research, statistical and survey purposes; and
  * as part of our efforts to keep our Site safe and secure.

We may combine technical information with other information that we have about you to help us with our processing of your information as described in this Policy.

#### Use of your data for marketing and communications

Sometimes we may use your personal information to provide marketing messages to you or allow us or third parties to communicate with you on third party services. We will always seek your consent before doing so and you can opt out of marketing and other communications at any time by contacting us here. You can always make use of the Site without having to agree to marketing. The types of things that we may do include:

  * providing direct marketing advertisements and communications to you via email, text, post or telephone or via our selected third parties;
  * making suggestions and recommendations to you and other users of our Site about goods or services that may interest you or them;
  * communicating with you on third party social media platforms and sharing your information with that social media platform;
  * providing your information to selected third parties that we believe may be able to offer you goods or services that are of interest so that they can contact you about their goods and services; and
  * monitoring the effectiveness of our direct marketing communications and your responses to it.

### WHO HAS ACCESS TO YOUR PERSONAL DATA?

We retain access to all personal information that we have collected from you or about you. Once your information has been passed to one of our members in the course of providing our services (most typically when you communicate with an estate agent through our Site) then that Rightmove member will have a copy of the information that you have provided about the property enquiry and your contact details which they will use to get in touch with you. Once in their possession, our member will be responsible for that information and that information will be subject to any privacy terms or policies that the member has in place; we are not responsible for use (or misuse) of your information by any of our members.

When our service is available via the websites of our partners, those partners may have access to your information. We may also have links to other websites from our Site. We are not responsible for the content, security, privacy policies and practices of any other websites, even if you access them using links from this Site or if you can access this Site or use our services from them. We recommend that you check the policy of each website that you visit and make sure that you are comfortable with the terms of such policies before providing any personal information.

If our business is sold or merged, or if we sell or buy any business or assets, we may disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets. We will make sure that any such transfer is done in a secure way.

If we offer or supply a service to you that is provided on our behalf by a third party we may have to pass your information to them in order to deliver the service. By using this Site you consent to us providing your information to the third parties authorised by us to provide such services. We may also use third parties to provide services on our behalf which may include processing (but not using themselves) your information e.g. to complete partial addresses or to augment the information we hold about you. In either case, we will not pass your information to anyone who is not also subject to adequate privacy commitments in our contract with them and we will not allow the third party to use your information for marketing purposes without your consent.

We will not otherwise disclose, sell or distribute your information to any third party without your permission unless we are required to do so by law or to obtain professional advice. We will retain your information for as long as is reasonable and necessary and no longer than permitted by law.

### WHERE DO WE STORE YOUR PERSONAL DATA?

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area (" **EEA** "). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers or contractors. Territories outside of the EEA may not have equivalent legal protections to those that apply within the EEA but we are under a duty to make sure that our suppliers and contractors located outside of the EEA continue to take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Policy. By submitting your personal data to us, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our Site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

We follow strict security procedures to ensure that your personal information is not damaged, destroyed or disclosed to a third party without your permission and to prevent unauthorised access to it. The computers that store the information are kept in a secure facility with restricted physical access and we use secure firewalls and other measures to restrict electronic access. If we are working with third parties, we will require them to have in place similar measures to protect your information.

Only employees who need access to your information to perform a specific job are granted access to personally identifiable information. We may require you to co-operate with our security checks before we disclose information to you. If you are a registered user, you can update the personal information that you give us at any time by viewing your [My Details page](https://www.rightmove.co.uk/login.html).

Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of the Site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share your password with anyone.

### YOUR RIGHTS

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data at any time.

You have the right to use our Site without consenting to marketing and communication services that we provide. We will inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. We always use the most recently submitted form to be your current consent status. If you are a registered user, but not signed in when you submit a form, we will not be able to use your saved settings so will deem your consent choice to be as per the form you submit at the time. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by ticking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your data. You can also exercise the right at any time by contacting us here.

The Data Protection Act 1998 (DPA) gives you the right to access information held about you. Your right of access can be exercised in accordance with the DPA. Any access request may be subject to a fee of £10 to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you.

### COOKIES AND TRACKING

Like many websites, we use "cookies" to enable us to personalise your visits to our Site, simplify the signing-in procedure, keep track of your preferences and to track the usage of our Site. For full details about what cookies we set and why we use them, please see our [Cookie Policy available here](http://www.rightmove.co.uk/this-site/cookies.html).

### CHANGES TO THIS POLICY

Any changes we may make to this Policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail. Please check back frequently to see any updates or changes to this Policy.
